The case that ended it all.
The Conjuring: Last Rites is a horror film directed by Michael Chaves.
Paranormal investigators Ed and Lorraine Warren take on one last
terrifying case involving mysterious entities they must confront.
Ed Warren, played by Patrick Wilson.
Lorraine Warren, played by Vera Farmiga.
Judy Warren, played by Mia Tomlinson.
Tony Spera, played by Ben Hardy.
Janet Smurl, played by Rebecca Calder.
Carin Smurl, played by Tilly Walker.
The Conjuring: Last Rites is a 2025 American supernatural horror film directed by Michael Chaves
and written by Ian Goldberg, Richard Naing, and David Leslie Johnson-McGoldrick.
The film is the ninth installment in The Conjuring film series, and is based
on the real-life investigations of the Smurl haunting case.
It stars Patrick Wilson and Vera Farmiga, who reprise their roles as paranormal
investigators Ed and Lorraine Warren, along with Mia Tomlinson and Ben Hardy.
The Conjuring: Last Rites was released in the United
States on September 5, 2025, by Warner Bros.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $494.7
million, becoming the highest-grossing film in the series.
A prequel, The Conjuring: The First Communion, is set
to be released on September 10, 2027.
The film explores themes of pennsylvania, usa,
supernatural, exorcism, haunted house, sequel.
The tone is dark.